Norman Vincent Peale Papers
Norman Vincent Peale Papers
1920-1965
Peale, Norman Vincent, 1898-1993.
400.0 linear ft. (ca.)
Papers of the American clergyman, author. Collection includes correspondence, manuscripts, and personal files; material relating to the American Foundation of Religion and Psychiatry, Guideposts, the Marble Collegiate Church, the Committee on Constitutional Government, family affairs, Peale's Look magazine and syndicated columns, pastoral counseling, his radio program Art of Living, and sermons. There is also material about the Kennedy campaign, including discussion of the election of a Roman Catholic, and letters concerning Peale's stand on religious freedom. Correspondents include Smiley Blanton, Dale Carnegie, Stanley S. Kresge, Leonard E. LeSourd, Fulton Oursler, and Lowell Thomas.
149462
Biographical History
Dr. Norman Vincent Peale (1898-1993) was an American Protestant preacher and author, best known for his The Power of Positive Thinking.
Born in Bowersville, Ohio, Peale attended Ohio Wesleyan University and Boston University School of Theology. He was ordained as a Methodist minister in 1922 but changed his affiliation to Reformed Church in America in 1932. Soon after, he became pastor of Marble Collegiate Church in Manhattan a post he kept for 52 years. All of Peale's projects were equally long-lived: his radio program, "The Art of Living," ran from 1935-1989, and in 1945, with his wife Ruth, he founded the popular Guideposts magazine which he served as editor for nearly fifty years and which is still published today.
With psychoanalyst Smiley Blanton, Peale set up a religio-psychiatric outpatient clinic next door to Marble Collegiate Church, with Blanton handling psychiatric issues and Peale religious issues. The two co-wrote several books, including Faith Is the Answer (1940). By 1951 the clinic had evolved into an independent organization, the American Foundation of Religion and Psychiatry, with Peale as president and Blanton as executive director. Peale was also a co-founder in 1947 of the Horatio Alger Association.
Over his career Peale wrote hundreds of sermons, articles, and papers and wrote or co-wrote more than forty inspirational or religious books. In 1963 a film, One Man's Way, based on his life and work was produced, and in 1984 Peale received the Presidential Medal of Freedom for his contributions to theology.
Scope and Contents of the Collection
The Norman Vincent Peale Papers are divided into four series: Correspondence, Subject files, Manuscripts, and Personal files. The material is further divided as follows:
Series I Correspondence (402 boxes) is divided into three subseries:
A: General Correspondence
B: Special Correspondence
C: Regular Correspondence
Series II Subject File (44 boxes) is divided into eleven subseries:
A: Prayer Correspondence
B: Problem Correspondence
C: Look Correspondence
D: Radio File
E: Sermon File
F: Kennedy Campaign
G: Marble Collegiate Church - 100th Anniversary
H: Research Materials
J: Testimonial Dinner
K: Guideposts
L: Sermon Publications
Series III Manuscripts (9 boxes) is divided into two parts:
A: Manuscripts by Dr. Peale
B: Manuscripts by Others
Series IV Personal file (16 boxes) is divided into two parts:
A: General File
B: Published Material
For further information see the individual series descriptions below.
Unprocessed additions
There is also a substantial amount of unprocessed material accessible only with special permission. Please contact the repository listed above for more information.
Arrangement of the Collection
The majority of material is arranged chronologically and within that alphabetically. See individual series descriptions below for more details.
Related Material
See also the
Ruth S. Peale Papers
.
Subject and Genre Headings
Church and clergy; Popular culture; Religion and philosophy; Blanton, Smiley, 1882-1966.; Carnegie, Dale, 1888-1955.; Kresge, Stanley Sebastian, 1900-; LeSourd, Leonard E.; Oursler, Fulton, 1893-1952.; Peale, Norman Vincent, 1898-1993.; Peale, Ruth Stafford, 1906-; Thomas, Lowell, 1892-1981.; American Foundation of Religion and Psychiatry.; Marble Collegiate Church (New York, N.Y.); Reformed Church in America -- Clergy.; Guideposts (Pawling, N.Y.); Christian life.; Christianity and politics.; Clergy -- United States.; Clergy as authors.; Devotional literature.; Mental health -- Religious aspects.; Pastoral counseling.; Peace of mind -- Religious aspects.; Psychology, Applied.; Radio in religion.; Religious newspapers and periodicals.; Sermons, American.; Success -- Religious aspects -- Christianity.; Clippings (information artifacts); Correspondence.; Diaries.; Leaflets.; Manuscripts for publication.; Sermons.; Authors.; Clergy.
Access Restrictions
The majority of our archival and manuscript collections are housed offsite and require advanced notice for retrieval. Researchers are encouraged to contact us in advance concerning the collection material they wish to access for their research.
Written permission of George Hart required to view materials in this collection.
Inventory
- I. Correspondence
  Correspondence is divided into A) General correspondence; B) Special correspondence; C) Regular correspondence.
  - A: General correspondence
    General correspondence is composed of both incoming and outgoing correspondence of a general nature. In this group are letters dealing with such diverse subjects as welcoming people to the Marble Collegiate Church, and the arrangements made concerning the appearance of the Peales on the Edward R. Murrow, Person-to-Person Show. This subseries is arranged chronologically, and then alphabetically, within each year.
    - General, 1934-1937
      - A-D (Box I:A:1)
      - E-L (Box I:A:2)
    - General, 1942
      - A-C (Box I:A:3)
      - D-G (Box I:A:4)
      - H-L (Box I:A:5)
      - M-P (Box I:A:6)
      - Q-S (Box I:A:7)
      - T-Z (Box I:A:8)
    - General, 1943
      - A-B (Box I:A:9)
      - C-D (Box I:A:10)
      - E-H (Box I:A:11)
      - H-L (Box I:A:12)
      - M-O (Box I:A:13)
      - P-R (Box I:A:14)
      - S-U (Box I:A:15)
      - V-Z (Box I:A:16)
    - General, 1944
      - C-F (Box I:A:17)
      - Fr-H (Box I:A:18)
      - In-Mi (Box I:A:19)
      - McA-Rz (Box I:A:20)
      - S-T (Box I:A:21)
      - Tr-Z (Box I:A:22)
    - General, 1945
      - A-Ci (Box I:A:23)
      - Cj-F (Box I:A:24)
      - H-Jm (Box I:A:25)
      - Jn-M (Box I:A:26)
      - Mn-P (Box I:A:27)
      - Q-Ti (Box I:A:28)
      - Tj-Z (Box I:A:29)
    - General, 1946
      - A-Bz (Box I:A:30)
      - C-Ei (Box I:A:31)
      - Ej-Hi (Box I:A:32)
      - Hj-L (Box I:A:33)
      - L-O (Box I:A:34)
      - P-Rz (Box I:A:35)
      - S-U (Box I:A:36)
      - V-Z (Box I:A:37)
      - Reinvestment Folder (Box I:A:37)
    - General, 1947
      - A-B (Box I:A:38)
      - C-Di (Box I:A:39)
      - Dj-F (Box I:A:40)
      - G-I (Box I:A:41)
      - J-L (Box I:A:42)
      - M-N (Box I:A:43)
      - O-Q (Box I:A:44)
      - R-S (Box I:A:45)
      - T-Z (Box I:A:46)
    - General, 1948
      - A-Bq (Box I:A:47)
      - Br-C (Box I:A:48)
      - D-Gj (Box I:A:49)
      - Gk-I (Box I:A:50)
      - J-L (Box I:A:51)
      - M-Ni (Box I:A:52)
      - Nj-Pe (Box I:A:53)
      - Pp-R (Box I:A:54)
      - S-T (Box I:A:55)
      - U-Y (Box I:A:56)
    - General, 1949
      - A-Bq (Box I:A:57)
      - Br-C (Box I:A:58)
      - Co-D (Box I:A:59)
      - E-G (Box I:A:60)
      - H-I (Box I:A:61)
      - J-L (Box I:A:62)
      - Ma-Nh (Box I:A:63)
      - Ni-P (Box I:A:64)
      - Q-So (Box I:A:65)
      - S-V (Box I:A:66)
      - W-Z (Box I:A:67)
    - General, 1950
      - A-B (Box I:A:68)
      - C (Box I:A:69)
      - D-F (Box I:A:70)
      - G-H (Box I:A:71)
      - I-L (Box I:A:72)
      - M-Mo (Box I:A:73)
      - Mn-Pd (Box I:A:74)
      - Pe-Rh (Box I:A:75)
      - Ri-So (Box I:A:76)
      - Sq-Tq (Box I:A:77)
      - Tr-We (Box I:A:78)
      - Wf-Z (Box I:A:79)
    - General, 1951
      - A-Bd (Box I:A:80)
      - Be-Ci (Box I:A:81)
      - Cj-Dal (Box I:A:82)
      - Dam-E (Box I:A:83)
      - F-G (Box I:A:84)
      - H (Box I:A:85)
      - H-Ki (Box I:A:86)
      - Kj-Ma (Box I:A:87)
      - Mc-Mz (Box I:A:88)
      - N-Pd (Box I:A:89)
      - Pe-Ri (Box I:A:90)
      - Rj-S (Box I:A:91)
      - T-V (Box I:A:92)
      - W-Z (Box I:A:93)
    - General, 1952
      - A-B (Box I:A:94)
      - B-C (Box I:A:95)
      - Cr-Di (Box I:A:96)
      - Dj-F (Box I:A:97)
      - G-Ha (Box I:A:98)
      - Hb-I (Box I:A:99)
      - J-K (Box I:A:100)
      - L-Mc (Box I:A:101)
      - Md-N (Box I:A:102)
      - N-Po (Box I:A:103)
      - Pp-So (Box I:A:104)
      - Sp-T (Box I:A:105)
      - Tr-Z (Box I:A:106)
    - General, 1953
      - A-Bd (Box I:A:107)
      - Bc-Bz (Box I:A:108)
      - C-Cn (Box I:A:109)
      - Co-Di (Box I:A:110)
      - Dj-F (Box I:A:111)
      - G-Hm (Box I:A:112)
      - Hn-J (Box I:A:113)
      - K-Lh (Box I:A:114)
      - Li-Mb (Box I:A:115)
      - Mc-Ni (Box I:A:116)
      - Nj-Pe (Box I:A:117)
      - Q-R (Box I:A:118)
      - S-So (Box I:A:119)
      - Sp-T (Box I:A:120)
      - U-We (Box I:A:121)
      - Wf-Y (Box I:A:122)
      - Barcus, Orville (Box I:A:122)
    - General, 1954-1960
      - A-Ap (Box I:A:123)
      - Aq-Be (Box I:A:124)
      - Bf-Br (Box I:A:125)
      - Bs-Ci (Box I:A:126)
      - Cm-Cz (Box I:A:127)
      - D (Box I:A:128)
      - E-Fe (Box I:A:129)
      - Ff-Fre (Box I:A:130)
      - Frf-G (Box I:A:131)
      - Ha (Box I:A:132)
      - Hb-Hud (Box I:A:133)
      - Hue-J (Box I:A:134)
      - K (Box I:A:135)
      - L-Lon (Box I:A:136)
      - Loo-Ma (Box I:A:137)
      - Mb-Moo (Box I:A:138)
      - Mop-N (Box I:A:139)
      - O-Pa (Box I:A:140)
      - Pf-Por (Box I:A:141)
      - Pos-Ri (Box I:A:142)
      - Rj-Sa (Box I:A:143)
      - Sb-Smi (Box I:A:144)
      - Smj-Sto (Box I:A:145)
      - Stp-T (Box I:A:146)
      - U-We (Box I:A:147)
      - Wf-Wz (Box I:A:148)
      - Y-Z (Box I:A:149)
    - General, 1960-1962
      - A-At (Box I:A:150)
      - Au-Be (Box I:A:151)
      - Be-Bo (Box I:A:152)
      - Bp-C (Box I:A:153)
      - Ca-Ci (Box I:A:154)
      - Cl-Cox (Box I:A:155)
      - Cr-Dey (Box I:A:156)
      - Di-Er (Box I:A:157)
      - Es-Fo (Box I:A:158)
      - Fr-Gra (Box I:A:159)
      - Gre-Har (Box I:A:160)
      - Has-Hos (Box I:A:161)
      - Hot-Ju (Box I:A:162)
      - K (Box I:A:163)
      - L-Lo (Box I:A:164)
      - Lu-Mc (Box I:A:165)
      - Me-Mz (Box I:A:166)
      - N (Box I:A:167)
      - O (Box I:A:168)
      - P-Pl (Box I:A:169)
      - Pg-Rf (Box I:A:170)
      - Rg-Rr (Box I:A:171)
      - Rs-S (Box I:A:172)
      - Sat-Sl (Box I:A:173)
      - Sm-Sto (Box I:A:174)
      - Ss-Tf (Box I:A:175)
      - Tg-U (Box I:A:176)
      - V-Wey (Box I:A:177)
      - Wha-Wz (Box I:A:178)
      - X-Z (Box I:A:179)
  - B: Special correspondence
    Special correspondence is divided into three parts: Norman Vincent Peale Correspondence; Joe Levy files; Dr. Leonard Le Sourd files
    - Norman Vincent Peale correspondence
      This subseries contains material relating to the Marble Collegiate Church, Committee on Constitutional Government, Dr. Peale's family and his syndicated columns. Included is correspondence between Dr. Peale and Dr. Smiley Blanton, who together founded the American Foundation of Religion and Psychiatry. It also contains correspondence between Dr. Peale and Lowell Thomas, Stanley S. Kresge, Dr. Leonard Le Sourd, W. Clement Stone, and J. Edgar Hoover. Notable among his foreign correspondents in this series is Madame Chiang Kai-Shek.
      - Correspondence, 1932-1943
        - A (Box I:B:1)
        - Abingdon Book Folder, 1940 (Box I:B:1)
        - Anti-Saloon League (Box I:B:1)
        - Association of Ministers (Box I:B:1)
        - Astor Hotel Meetings, 1941 (Box I:B:1)
        - B-Bi (Box I:B:1)
        - Bakke, Loletta (Box I:B:1)
        - Baseball Passes, 1940-1941 (Box I:B:1)
        - Mr. Bertholf re: Church Survey, 1939-1940 (Box I:B:1)
        - Birthday Greetings, 1933 (Box I:B:2)
        - Bj-Bg, 1932-1943 (Box I:B:2)
        - Blanton, Dr. Smiley, 1937-1940 (Box I:B:2)
        - Mr. Blumenfeld, Case History, 1939 (Box I:B:2)
        - Book Account from March, 1941 - ("Art of Living," "You Can Win," "Faith is the Answer") (Box I:B:2)
        - Book List II - Answers, 1932-1943 (Box I:B:2)
        - Book List II - Answers - (Includes Comments by Authors re: Pornographic Literature), 1941 (Box I:B:2)
        - Book List II - Publicity, 1941 (Box I:B:2)
        - Book List III -, 1941 (Box I:B:2)
        - "Books That Have Interested Me" N.V.P. (mss) (Box I:B:2)
        - Budget, 1933 (Box I:B:2)
        - Budget, Answers to Letters, 1935 (Box I:B:2)
        - Bulletins for Hotels, 1932-1934 (Box I:B:2)
        - Br-Bz (Box I:B:3)
        - Calendar File, 1932-1933; 1933-1934,; 1934-1935 (Box I:B:3)
        - Calendars of Other Churches, 1943 (Box I:B:3)
        - Chase, Theo. I., Estate, 1940-1941 (Box I:B:4)
        - Choir Letters - Personal, 1941 (Box I:B:4)
        - Christian Endeavor, 1939; 1941 (Box I:B:4)
        - Christian Endeavor Nominating Committee, 1941 (Box I:B:4)
        - Classis, 1943 (Box I:B:4)
        - Clippings, 1940 (Box I:B:4)
        - Committee on Constitutional Government
          - Post Election Correspondence; Rumely, 1940-1941 (Box I:B:4)
          - Book Intro.: "The Last Best Hope of Man", 1943 (Box I:B:5)
          - Ministers' Letters, 1943 (Box I:B:5)
          - Speech Material, 1943 (Box I:B:5)
        - Congratulatory Letters re: Installation, 1932 (Box I:B:6)
        - Consistory, 1943 (Box I:B:6)
        - Dedication of Burrel Hall (1/25/38), 1937-1938 (Box I:B:6)
        - Denison, William S., 1932-1935 (Box I:B:6)
        - Dictaphone File (Box I:B:6)
        - Dies Committee (American Youth Congress), 1939-1940 (Box I:B:6)
        - Easter Letters, 1940 (Box I:B:6)
        - Easter Letters, 1943 (Box I:B:6)
        - Elberon Church, 1940-1941 (Box I:B:7)
        - Elberon Church, 1943 (Box I:B:7)
        - Eubank Correspondence, 1940 (Box I:B:7)
        - European Trip, 1933 (Box I:B:7)
        - "Faith is the Answer,", 1940-1941; 1943 (Box I:B:7)
        - First Methodist Episcopal Church, 1932 (Box I:B:7)
        - Flatlands Methodist Episcopal Church (Box I:B:7)
        - Hollywood, 1941 - Personal, 1943 (Box I:B:7)
        - Home Library (T.B. Costain), 1941 (Box I:B:7)
        - Installations, 1933 (Box I:B:7)
        - Japanese Worth, 1943 (Box I:B:7)
        - Junior Guild, 1943 (Box I:B:7)
        - Kagawa Dinner, 1936 (Box I:B:7)
        - Kansas University, Dec. 1941-Jan. 1942 (Box I:B:7)
        - Legion of Decency, 1941 (Box I:B:7)
        - Letters of Reference, 1943 (Box I:B:7)
        - Mack, J.S. - Radio Fund (Box I:B:8)
        - Macy, M.S., 1941-1942 (Box I:B:8)
        - Marble Collegiate Church, 1938 (Box I:B:8)
        - Marble Collegiate Church, 85th Anniversary, 1939 (Box I:B:8)
        - Men's Group for Action and Prayer, 1940 (Box I:B:8)
        - Men's League (J.E. Penney), 1943 (Box I:B:8)
        - Murphy, Rev. Harry W., 1933 (Box I:B:8)
        - Musical Positions, Applications for, 1937-1941 (Box I:B:8)
        - National Conference of Christians and Jews (Box I:B:8)
        - National Temperance Society, 1939-1943 (Box I:B:8)
        - New York Civic League, 1939 (Box I:B:8)
        - Newman, Cassie (Box I:B:8)
        - News Releases - Carbons, 1941 (Box I:B:8)
        - News Releases - Mr. Goodman, 1940 (Box I:B:8)
        - Ney, Major F.J., 1940 (Box I:B:9)
        - Notes on Dr. Peale's Books, 1939-1940 (Box I:B:9)
        - Ocean Grove (Box I:B:9)
        - "One Foot in Heaven", 1941; 1943 (Box I:B:9)
        - Pawling, 1943 (Box I:B:9)
        - Peale Family, 1941; 1943 (Box I:B:9)
        - Peale, Dr. C.C., 1939-1941; 1943 (Box I:B:9)
        - Peale, Rev. Leonard, 1939-1941; 1943 (Box I:B:9)
        - Peale, N.V., 1942-1943; biographies; correspondence; personal; 10th Anniversary (Box I:B:9)
        - Peale, Dr. Robert, 1939-1941; 1943 (Box I:B:9)
        - Peale, Misc. Relatives, 1939-1941 (Box I:B:9)
        - Mr. Peat, 1943 (Box I:B:10)
        - Pettingill Releases, 1940-1941 (Box I:B:10)
        - Pettingill, Samuel B., 1943 (Box I:B:10)
        - Preaching Mission (Box I:B:10)
        - Presbyterian Hospital Bed, 1941 (Box I:B:10)
        - Presbyterian Ministers' Fund, 1943 (Box I:B:10)
        - President's Council, 1942 (Box I:B:10)
        - Pulpit Supply Letters, 1941 (Box I:B:10)
        - Questionnaires for New Members, 1934 (Box I:B:10)
        - Reeves Case, 1943 (Box I:B:10)
        - Rehberg Correspondence, 1943 (Box I:B:10)
        - "The Right to Work", 1943 (Box I:B:10)
        - Rochester - Surrendered File, 1935-1936 (Box I:B:10)
        - Rumely, Edward A., 1940 (Box I:B:10)
        - St. Louis, Mo. (Box I:B:10)
        - Smith, Dr. L.E.H., 1940 (Box I:B:10)
        - Special Work Committee, 1904-1941 (Box I:B:10)
        - Special Work Folder (Box I:B:10)
        - Speech Material - Savings Bonds, 1941 (Box I:B:10)
        - Staples, Lillian - Case History, 1939 (Box I:B:11)
        - Stauter, Wesley A, 1934-1935 (Box I:B:11)
        - Summer Hotels, 1933 (Box I:B:11)
        - Summer Supply Letters, 1939-1943 (Box I:B:11)
        - Swallow, Edith, 1940-1941 (Box I:B:11)
        - Telegrams (Box I:B:11)
        - Tenement House, 1934 (Box I:B:11)
        - Third Term - Radio Talk - Carnegie Hall, 1940 (Box I:B:11)
        - Third Term Folder - Unfavorable, 1940 (Box I:B:11)
        - Third Term Stand - Favorable Letters, 1940 (Box I:B:12)
        - Undercover, 1943 (Box I:B:12)
        - Wade, Bishop, 1943 (Box I:B:12)
        - Mrs. Waitt, 1939 (Box I:B:12)
        - Warner Bros. (Box I:B:12)
        - Weiss, Rose, and Case Histories (Box I:B:12)
        - Wertheim Material (Box I:B:12)
        - Willkie's Speeches, 1941 (Box I:B:12)
        - XYZ (Box I:B:12)
      - Correspondence, 1944
        - Abingdon - Cokesbury (Box I:B:13)
        - Associated Ministers (Box I:B:13)
        - Astor Meeting Blackout (Box I:B:13)
        - Blanton, Dr. Smiley (Box I:B:13)
        - Book Publishers (Box I:B:13)
        - Camden Engagements (Box I:B:13)
        - Christian Endeavor (Box I:B:13)
        - Christian Herald (Box I:B:13)
        - Church Council (Box I:B:13)
        - Classis (Box I:B:13)
        - Collegiate Church Office (Box I:B:13)
        - Committee for Constitutional Government, A-Q (Box I:B:13)
        - Committee for Constitutional Government, R-Z; General; Dr. Rumely Consistory (Box I:B:14)
        - Consistorial Reports, April 1944 (Box I:B:14)
        - Congressional Investigation (Box I:B:14)
        - "Courage to Live" (Box I:B:14)
        - Criticism, Letters of (Box I:B:14)
        - Elberon Church (Box I:B:15)
        - Federation of Churches (Box I:B:15)
        - "Guideposts, Inc." (Box I:B:15)
        - Gwinn, Ralph W. (Box I:B:15)
        - Junior Guild (Box I:B:15)
        - Laymen's Committee (Box I:B:15)
        - Marble Church Fire (Box I:B:15)
        - Matsumoto, Toru (Box I:B:15)
        - McKay, Paul L. (Box I:B:15)
        - Men's League (Box I:B:15)
        - Midweek Services (Box I:B:15)
        - Mobilization / Spiritual Mobilization (Box I:B:15)
        - National Conference of Christians and Jews (Box I:B:15)
        - National Temperance Society (Box I:B:15)
        - New Brunswick (Box I:B:15)
        - Newspaper Comment - 19th Anniversary Service (Box I:B:16)
        - 19th Anniversary Service (Box I:B:16)
        - Ocean Grove (Box I:B:16)
        - Palestine, Christian Council On (Box I:B:16)
        - Pawling (Box I:B:16)
        - Peale, Others in Family (Box I:B:16)
        - Peale, Dr. C.C. (Box I:B:16)
        - Peale, Rev. Leonard (Box I:B:16)
        - Peale, Norman Vincent - Personal (Box I:B:16)
        - Peale, Capt. Robert C. (Box I:B:16)
        - Peale, Robert W. (Box I:B:16)
        - Peat, Harold (Box I:B:16)
        - Peck, George (Box I:B:16)
        - Pettingill, Samuel B. (Box I:B:17)
        - Political Action Members (Box I:B:17)
        - Prospective Members (Box I:B:17)
        - Purkas, Ada
        - Rager, Earl A. (Box I:B:17)
        - Reeves, Rev. John R. (Box I:B:17)
        - Reference Letters (Box I:B:17)
        - Reformed Church (Box I:B:17)
        - "Right to Work" (Box I:B:17)
        - Rotary (Box I:B:17)
        - Servicemen's Christian League (Box I:B:17)
        - Soldier's Mail (Box I:B:17)
        - Soundscriber (Box I:B:17)
        - Speaking Engagements Not Filled (Box I:B:17)
        - Speaking Engagements Rejected (Box I:B:18)
        - Special Work Committee (Box I:B:18)
        - Staff Memos (Box I:B:18)
        - Summer Supplies (Box I:B:18)
        - Sunday Memos (Box I:B:18)
        - Testimonial Dinner (Box I:B:18)
        - Testimonial Letters (Box I:B:19)
        - Waldorf Ballroom Meetings (Box I:B:19)
        - Y.M.C.A. (Box I:B:19)
      - Correspondence, 1945
        - Baptisms (Box I:B:19)
        - Book Correspondence (Box I:B:19)
        - Book List (Box I:B:19)
        - Book Publishers (Box I:B:19)
        - Blanton, Dr. Smiley (Box I:B:19)
        - Bretz, Alice Budget (Box I:B:19)
        - Christian Century Articles (Box I:B:19)
        - Christian Endeavor (Box I:B:19)
        - Christian Herald (Box I:B:19)
        - Church Clinic (Box I:B:20)
        - Classis (Box I:B:20)
        - Collegiate Church (Box I:B:20)
        - Constitutional Government, A-Z; General; Dr. Rumely; Detroit (Box I:B:20)
        - Detroit (Box I:B:20)
        - Elberon Church (Box I:B:21)
        - Executives' Club (Box I:B:21)
        - Federation of Churches (Box I:B:21)
        - Junior Guild (Box I:B:21)
        - Lenten Reading List (Box I:B:21)
        - Members, New (Box I:B:21)
        - Men's League (Box I:B:21)
        - Mobilization (Box I:B:21)
        - National Temperance Society (Box I:B:21)
        - New Book on Drinking (Box I:B:21)
        - New Brunswick Theological Seminary (Box I:B:21)
        - Newspaper Releases, Excerpts, Prayers, Etc. (Box I:B:21)
        - Ocean Grove (Box I:B:21)
        - Pawling (Box I:B:21)
        - Peale - Others in Family (Box I:B:21)
        - Peale, Dr. C.C. (Box I:B:21)
        - Peale, Rev. Leonard (Box I:B:21)
        - Peale, Norman Vincent (Box I:B:21)
        - Peale, Norman Vincent - Correspondence (Box I:B:22)
        - Peale, Capt. Robert C. (Box I:B:22)
        - Peale, Robert W. (Box I:B:22)
        - Peat, Harold (Box I:B:22)
        - Peck, George (Box I:B:22)
        - Pettingill, Samuel B. (Box I:B:22)
        - Pew, J. Howard (Box I:B:22)
        - Picture Stories from the Bible (Box I:B:22)
        - Presbyterian Ministers' Fund (Box I:B:22)
        - The Protestant (Box I:B:23)
        - Railroad Workers' Journal (Box I:B:23)
        - Reference Letters (Box I:B:23)
        - Reformed Church (Box I:B:23)
        - Rotary (Box I:B:23)
        - Sales Executive club (Box I:B:23)
        - Sermon Committee (Box I:B:23)
        - Sermon Excerpts (Box I:B:23)
        - Servicemen's Christian League (Box I:B:23)
        - Servicemen's Committee (Box I:B:23)
        - Soldier's Mail (Box I:B:23)
        - Soundscriber (Box I:B:23)
        - Speaking Engagements not Filled (Box I:B:23)
        - Speaking Engagements Rejected, A-I (Box I:B:23)
        - Speaking Engagements Rejected J-Z (Box I:B:24)
        - Special Work Committee (Box I:B:24)
        - Staff Memos (Box I:B:24)
        - Summer Supplies (Box I:B:24)
        - Sunday Memos (Box I:B:24)
        - Town Hall Meetings (Box I:B:24)
        - Under Cover (Box I:B:24)
        - Undercover - Letters to send out with replies (Box I:B:24)
        - V.E. Day (Box I:B:24)
        - "Woman's Home Companion" (Box I:B:24)
        - Y.M.C.A. (Box I:B:24)
      - Correspondence, 1946
        - Abingdon - Cokesbury Press (Box I:B:25)
        - Advertising (Box I:B:25)
        - American Magazine (Box I:B:25)